Matthew Lyon

Manchester, United Kingdom

I am currently a PhD student in the Machine Learning group at the University of Manchester. My research focuses on improving MRI data through deep learning, and incorporating geometric priors into deep learning models. I have prior experience working as a research software engineer at several research institutes.

Education

2020 - 2024 **PhD in Computer Science,** *University of Manchester*

United Kingdom

2015 - 2016 **Master of Medical Physics,** *University of Sydney*

Australia

2011 - 2014 BSc (Hons) in Physics, University of Warwick

United Kingdom

Professional Experience

06/2022 - 04/2023 Scientific Consultant, ACCS

Stockport, UK Part Time 0.3 FTE

• Developed SQL database backend and frontend UI

• Performed statistical analyses

Authored literature review for AI age assurance Ofcom report

08/2019 - 08/2020 **Research Software Engineer,** Save Sight Institute

Sydney, Australia Part Time 0.8 FTE

• Developed, tested, and documented neuroimaging processing pipelines.

· Lead algorithm design and optimisation workflows.

• Consulted on neuroimaging analysis techniques and signal processing.

08/2019 - 01/2020 **Neuroimaging Analyst,** Sydney Neuroimaging Research Centre

Sydney, Australia Part Time 0.4 FTE

• Developed and implemented neuroimaging analysis pipelines.

Performed QC on MRI analysis.

07/2017 - 07/2019 **Research Software Engineer,** Heart Research Institute

Sydney, Australia Full Time

Built and managed a distributed computing cluster.

• Developed, tested, and documented neuroimaging processing pipelines.

Oversaw data ingestion and QC/QA, created dashboard visualisations.

Conducted clinical research using MRI data.

Technologies

Python • TensorFlow • Keras • PyTorch • NumPy • TypeScript • React • Express • GraphQL

SQLite • MongoDB • C++ • Matlab • Bash • Docker • Ubuntu • OSX • Windows

_		•	-	•	
Pu	hΙ	10	at	10	nc

2023	Spatio-Angular Convolutions for Super-resolution in Diffusion MRI, NeurIPS 2023 Matthew Lyon, Paul Armitage, Mauricio A Álvarez
2022	Angular Super-Resolution in Diffusion MRI with a 3D Recurrent Convolutional Autoencoder, MIDL 2022 Matthew Lyon, Paul Armitage, Mauricio A. Álvarez
2019	Gender-specific structural abnormalities in major depressive disorder revealed by fixel-based analysis, NeuroImage: Clinical Matthew Lyon, Thomas Welton, Adrina Varda, Jerome J. Maller, Kathryn Broadhouse, Mayuresh S. Korgaonkar, Stephen H. Koslow, Leanne M. Williams, Evian Gordon, A. John Rush, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Is occipital bending a structural biomarker of risk for depression and sensitivity to treatment?, Journal of Clinical Neuroscience Karen Fullard, Jerome J. Maller, Thomas Welton, Matthew Lyon, Evian Gordon, Stephen H. Koslow, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Profound and reproducible patterns of reduced regional gray matter characterize major depressive disorder, <i>Translational Psychiatry</i> Sarah C. Hellewell, Thomas Welton, Jerome J. Maller, Matthew Lyon, Mayuresh S. Korgaonkar, Stephen H. Koslow, Leanne M. Williams, John A. Rush, Evian Gordon, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Structural core of the executive control network: A high angular resolution diffusion MRI study, Human Brain Mapping Kai-kai Shen, Thomas Welton, Matthew Lyon, Andrew N. McCorkindale, Greg T. Sutherland, Samantha Burnham, Jurgen Fripp, Ralph Martins, Stuart M. Grieve
Talks	
New Orleans, USA	Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems, NeurIPS 2023 Spatio-Angular Convolutions for Super-resolution in Diffusion MRI
Zurich, Switzerland	Medical Imaging with Deep Learning, MIDL 2022 ☑ Angular Super-Resolution in Diffusion MRI with a 3D Recurrent Convolutional Autoencoder
Manchester, United Kingdom	Advances in Data Science and AI Conference, ASDAI 2022 Angular Super-Resolution in Diffusion MRI with a 3D Recurrent Convolutional Autoencoder
Invited Reviewe	r
Hawaiʻi, USA	International Conference on Machine Learning, ICML 2023
Valencia, Spain	International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics, AISTATS 2022

New Orleans, USA Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems, NeurIPS 2022